こちらへ。
This way.
《マジってか…
あるんだな こんなこと》
Are you kidding me?
I can't believe this is happening...
Oops.
おっと！ 大丈夫か？
You okay?
あぁ サンキューってば… え？
Yeah!
Thanks, man.
Huh?
あ… あっ！
ああ～っ！
このやろ～！
You jerk!
ヘヘヘッ バチが当たった。
ぶっ殺す！
Divine retribution for you.
I'll kill that guy!
(ヤマト)はい ダメですよ。
Okay, that won't do.
クソソラが クソソラが… クソ！
Damn him, damn him,
damn him, damn him!
ニヒヒッ！
ソラ なんてことを！
Sora! What have you done?!
(ソラ)はいはい ボクが悪いです！
Okay, okay, my bad.
I'll kill him...
I'm definitely going to kill him.
殺す ぜってぇ殺す！
No, no, you'll receive
divine punishment if you do.
いやいや ホントにバチが当たるよ。
(忍僧たち)
おかえりなさいませ 地陸様。
Welcome back, Lord Chiriku.
(地陸)首尾は？
(忍僧)はっ！
How are things progressing?
Sir! We have already sent Shinobi monks
to the remaining three hidden tombs
(忍僧)すでに 他の３つの隠し墓➡
ナウマ様 トウウ様 セイト様の墓所に
忍僧たちを向かわせております。
of Lord Nauma, Lord Tou'u
and Lord Seito.
いずれも火ノ寺きっての手練れ。
They are all the finest of
Fire Temple monks
and arrangements have been made
for them to inform us immediately
異変があれば
直ちに知らせが入る手筈に…。
if something unusual happens.
キタネ様 ご遺骸の捜索には
数名をさいて当たっております。
We have assigned several men to
the search for the remains of Lord Kitane.
(忍僧)寺の警護も強化し
もしもの場合に備えております。
We have also tightened
temple security and are ready
just in case something happens.
ならば まずは安心か。
Then I suppose we can rest easy...
It took you guys long enough.
(ソラ)遅ぇんだよ。
Sora...!
(地陸)ソラ！
フンッ。
なに？ あの態度！
アイツ… ん？
He's sure got an attitude problem!
That jerk!
(地陸)ただいま戻りました。
We have returned.
These are the people from the Hidden Leaf
こちらは 私の要請に応えて
来てくださった➡
who came here in compliance
with our request.
木ノ葉の里の方々です。
Hello. I'm Captain Yamato.
どうも 隊長のヤマトです。
彼らは サクラ サイ ナルト。
And this is Sakura, Sai
and Naruto.
(高僧)木ノ葉の… それは心強い。
From the Leaf?
That is indeed reassuring.
That's right. Just leave it to us!
おう 任せておけってばよ！
We are prepared to move out
whenever necessary.
いつでも動けるよう
準備は できています。
いずれにせよ 忍僧たちからの
連絡を待ったうえで…。
Either way, you won't have to until
we hear from the Shinobi monks.
それまでは こちらで。
Until then, please come this way.
Loneliness
奪われた死体 何に使うのかな？
I wonder what they'll use...
the stolen bodies for.
そうだね。 遺体がもつ情報が
欲しかったのか あるいは…。
Well, maybe they wanted the information
the bodies held...
or perhaps...
((大蛇丸 : 口寄せ 穢土転生！
Summoning Jutsu: Reanimation!
１つ ２つ！
One! Two!
３人目は ダメだったようね。
It appears the third one didn't work out.
(まぁ いいわ))
Oh well...
大蛇丸のように 遺体そのものを
利用する目的なのかもしれない。
Their objective might be to use
the body itself as Orochimaru did.
まぁ
そんな高度な術を使える連中が➡
Well, I doubt you'd come across a group
そういるとは思えないけどね。
that can use a powerful Jutsu
like that every day.
へぇ～ んじゃ
その隠し墓に眠る４人の忍って➡
No kidding?
Then the four Ninja resting
in those hidden tombs
よっぽど偉かったんだな… うっ！
must've been really powerful.
な… 何？
Wh-What?
偉いヤツらでした。
そして 何より いいヤツらでした。
They were remarkable Shinobi.
And most of all, they were good people.
(地陸)火ノ寺を中心とする
東西南北に位置する場所に➡
The tombs of Nauma, Seito,
Tou'u and Kitane are located
ナウマ セイト トウウ そして
キタネの墓が置かれております。
to the east, west, south and north
with the Fire Temple as the central point.
彼らは いずれも
守護忍十二士のメンバーでありました。
They were all members of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
守護忍十二士…？
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve?
聞いたことがあります。
(サイ)名前だけは。
I've heard of them.
I've just heard the name.
あれ？ 有名なの…？
Huh? Are they famous?
まぁ 知る人ぞ知るって感じかな。
なっ…!?
Well, to those in the know,
I guess they're well known.
守護忍十二士とは
火ノ国の大名を守るために➡
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve
was an organization
comprised of elite Shinobi
gathered from within the nation
国じゅうから 精鋭を集めて
できた組織でね。
to protect the Feudal Lord of
the Land of Fire, you see.
Huh? But it's Shinobi from our Leaf Village
who protect the Land of Fire, right?
火ノ国を守るのは
オレたち 木ノ葉の里の忍だろ？
火ノ国を守るのは木ノ葉の里だよ。
Yes, the Hidden Leaf Village does
protect the Land of Fire.
でも里は あくまでも
国を守るための機関であって➡
But to be exact, a village is
an institution to protect the land.
大名個人を守るためだけの
組織じゃない。
It's not an organization
just for protecting
an individual Feudal Lord.
じゃあさ…。
Then...
国を守るには まず
その頂点である大名を守ること。
First, the Feudal Lord who is
the apex of the land,
must be protected in order
to protect that land.
(地陸)守護忍十二士とは
そのような考えを前提に➡
The Guardian Shinobi Twelve
is an organization
assembled with such
a concept as its foundation.
集められた組織なのです。
あの頃は 私も若かった。
I was also young back then.
火ノ国のため
命を投げ出すことも いとわぬと➡
I joined the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
willing to lay down my life
for the Land of Fire.
守護忍十二士に参加したのです。
じゃあ 地陸さんも…？
Then you were also...!
元… ですがね。
I used to be.
ちなみに アスマさんも
元 守護忍十二士なんだよ。
Incidentally, Asuma also
used to be a member
of the Twelve Guardian Shinobi Warriors.
(サクラ/ナルト)へぇ～！
- What?!
アスマか… 彼は 元気ですか？
Asuma, huh?
Is he doing okay?
元気だってばよ！
Yeah! He's good!
この前もさ
修業のアドバイス もらったんだぜ。
He gave me some training advice
the other day.
ほぅ… そうですか。
Oh... I see.
…ということは➡
So that means...
今回の事件は 地陸さんにとって
アスマ先生にとってもですが➡
This incident...
to you and to Asuma Sensei...
仲間の墓を荒らされた
ということなのですね？
It means your friends' graves
were violated, right?
あの４人は 火ノ国のため
若くして命を落としたのです。
Those four people lost their lives
at a young age
for the sake of the Land of Fire.
(地陸)守護人十二士の中に➡
Within the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
クーデターを起こそうとする
一派が現れ➡
a faction attempting to stage
a coup emerged...
and that ended up dividing the twelve.
それが 十二士を二分したのです。
クーデターとは 強引な手段に
訴えてでも➡
A coup is an attempt to change a land
自分たちの
理想とする考えに➡
into one's ideal notions even if it
means resorting to a forceful approach.
国を変えようとする
行為のことだよ。
知ってるよ そのくらい…。
Even I know that!
火ノ国を守りたい…
その思いが先鋭化して➡
People who radicalized the notion
of wanting to protect the Land of Fire
過激な考えを持つ者たちが➡
and who possessed extreme ideologies
守護忍十二士の中に
現れてしまった。
ended up emerging within
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
そうだよ！ つまりさ…。
That's right! In other words...!
火ノ国を なまぬるい
木ノ葉の里などに➡
They couldn't leave matters
of the Land of Fire
任せちゃおけないって
ことでしょう。
to the moderate Hidden Leaf Village.
自分たち中心に 軍事力を
強化した国をつくろう。
They wanted to create
a land of strengthened military force
with themselves at the center...
or something like that.
…ってところかな。
いや そういうところかな。
許せねえな！
Yeah, or something like that.
That's unforgivable!
(サクラ)ナルト！
うん？
Naruto!
うるさい！
Keep quiet!
(地陸)そう…
木ノ葉の里を解体し➡
Right... Their plan was to break up
the Leaf Village and turn that military force
その軍事力を
大名中心の機関とする。
into an institution with
the Feudal Lord at the center.
彼らのプランは 現実に
大名を動かすところまで➡
It proceeded so far as to influence
the Feudal Lord.
進められていました。
そして同時に➡
And at the same time,
他国への戦をも準備していた。
they were making preparations
to attack other lands.
何ですって！
What did you say?!
Without making do with peace forged
with a delicate balance
五大国間の微妙なバランスで
築いた平和を よしとせず➡
among the Five Great Nations,
火ノ国が世界を統一し➡
they waved the banner of
a noble cause in which
完全なる平和を手にするのだと
大義を掲げて…。
the Land of Fire would unite the world
and total peace would be attained.
そんな 勝手な…！
That's so selfish...
うむ… どんなに立派な
御託を並べても 戦は戦。
Yes... War is war,
no matter how splendid
the song and dance may be.
さすがに大名も 彼らの
いきすぎた考えに気づき➡
As expected,
the Feudal Lord became aware
of their radical thinking and...
そして…。
(地陸)クーデターを
起こした６人は死にました。
The six people who staged
the coup died.
However, Kitane, Nauma,
Tou'u and Seito...also fell victim.
しかし キタネ ナウマ トウウ セイトの
４人も犠牲になってしまった。
そんなことがあったなんて…。
I can't believe something
like that happened.
(サイ)隠し墓の４人は
地陸さんや アスマ先生の友達…。
The four people of
the hidden tombs were
friends of Chiriku and Asuma Sensei.
ナルトや サクラの友達…
例えば サスケ君が死んで➡
For example, let's say...
our friend Sasuke were to die
and his body were to be stolen...
その死体が盗まれたとしたら…。
そうだよね。
That's right.
キタネさんのご遺体を盗んだヤツを
許すわけにはいかない！
We can't forgive the people
who stole Kitane's body.
Yeah, it's unforgivable.
あぁ 許せねえ！
It's the night training for the boy monks.
少年僧たちの 夜の稽古です。
(少年僧たち)はっ はっ…！
It's that jerk, Sora.
ヘッ ソラのヤロウだってばよ！
Begin free sparring!
自由組手 はじめ！
ん？
なに？
What is it?
おかしいってばよ…。
だから 何が？
That's strange.
What is it already?
Oh! I'm getting ticked off!
あぁ～ ムカムカしてきた！
Bow!
(師範)礼！
(少年僧たち)
ありがとうございました！
- Thank you!
テメエ…。
なぁ こんなんでいいのか？
You...
Hey, is it okay like this?
テメエ ふざけてんのか？
Are you screwing around?
ふざけてんのは お前だろ？
You're the one who's screwing around.
稽古だかなんだかしんねえけど➡
I don't know if it's training or what,
but this is like what you're doing.
お前のやってることは
こんなもんだぜ。
この！
ムカムカすんだよ！
You jerk!
You really tick me off.
お前 バカにしてっだろ？
You're messing with me,
aren't you?
何かわかんねえけど
腹が立つんだってばよ！
I don't really know why
but you're making me angry!
ナルト！ あのバカ…。
Naruto...! That idiot!
お前 ナルトって言ったなぁ。
ああ。
Your name's Naruto, right?
Yeah.
もっといい名前をつけてやるよ。
Let me give you an even better one...
グッとくる戒名をよ！
I'll give you a deeply moving
posthumous name.
戒名？
Posthumous name?
ナルト！
Naruto!
やっと
本気になったみてえだなぁ！
It looks like you've
finally gotten serious.
さっき オレとやったときは
今みたいに強かったもんなぁ！
You were strong back
when you fought me...
like you are now!
お前 ムカツク…。
You really tick me off!
ちょっとこれ
激しすぎるんでないかい？
Isn't this...a little bit too intense?
(ソラ)またか…。
Not again...
うぉ～っ!!
《なんだ？ コイツ…。
What's with this guy?
急に 力が空回りしてる》
His power's suddenly
become ineffective.
《この目… ソラを？》
Those eyes...
They're looking at Sora?
《同じ目…》
It's the same eyes.
《なんで お前もあの目を…》
Why are they also looking
at you with those eyes?!
うぅ… うぉ～っ!!
やめなさい ソラ！
That's enough, Sora!
《やべぇ！ 止まらねえ!!》
I can't stop!
戒名 つけそこねたな…。
I failed to give you a posthumous name.
うわっ！ な… なんだよ!?
いや 汗をふいてあげようと…。
Whoa! What're you doing?!
I just thought I'd wipe off the sweat.
やめろよ。 気持わりい。
Cut it out! That's gross.
なぁ サイ…。
ん？
Hey, Sai.
戒名って なんだ？
What's a posthumous name?
まぁ… ニックネームみたいなものかな。
Well, I guess it's kind of like...
a nickname.
死者に対してですけど…。
あっ！
It's a name given to the dead.
お前がつけてる
あだ名みたいなもんか。
えっ？
So it's like the nicknames
you give people?!
友達の証しってことか。
That means
it's a sign of friendship, huh?!
ソラ！
Sora!
おい！
Hey!
ん？
あっ！
どうした？
What is it?!
(忍僧)ナウマ様の墓所が…。
Lord Nauma's grave site!
(ソラ)はぁっ！
獣波掌！
Beast Wave Palm!
獣波烈風掌！
Beast Wave: Palm Hurricane!
すっげぇな！ お前の術。
They're awesome...your Jutsu!
これも風のチャクラの
形態変化なのか？
Is this also the wind
Change in Chakra Form?
何しに来た？
ん？ あぁ。
What're you doing here?
Oh...
オレも お前に
戒名をつけてやろうってな。
I thought I'd give you
a posthumous name too!
いいぜ
いい戒名をつけてくれよ！
Fine... Give me a good one!
ソラ ゾラ… ソラッチ！
ソーラン ソランちゃん！
Sora! Sora! Sora-cchi.
Soran! Soran-chan.
テメエ ふざけやがって！
You jerk! Don't mess with me!
あの寺で 何があったんだよ。
What happened in that temple?
テメエ… うっとうしいぜ。
You're...an annoyance!
あぁ ガキの頃から
思われ続けてきたってばよ。
Yeah, people have kept thinking
that about me since I was little.
お前もなんだろ？
You, too... right?
だったら…！
Then...!
どうしたってんだよ。
What of it?
あぁ うっとうしがられてるよ。
Yeah! People think I'm a nuisance!
だが そんなことは屁でもねえ。
But something like that
doesn't bother me at all!
いちばん
オレをうっとうしく思ってんのは➡
I'm the one who thinks
I'm a nuisance the most of all!
このオレだからな！
そうよ。
That's right...
オレの力がよ うっとうしい。
My power is a nuisance.
お前…。
You...
でもな うっとうしくても
この力を捨てることはできねえ。
But nuisance or not,
I can't throw away this power.
オレの父さんを殺したヤツに
復讐するために。
Because I must have revenge...
on the one who killed my father.
復讐？
Revenge?!
あっ！ 物見鳥だ。
隠し墓か!?
It's a patrol bird! Is it the hidden tom
ナルト！ どこ行ってたのよ。
悪い。
(ヤマト)ナウマ様の隠し墓へ
向かった忍僧から 連絡があった。
墓が破られ ご遺体は
持ち去られたあとだったそうだ。
なんだって!?
クッ…！
このままでは あとの２つも…。
支度はできています
参りましょう。
オレも行きます！
よし。
よっしゃあ
小汚い墓泥棒なんざ➡
オレが ぶっ飛ばしてやる！
今日の質問は？
「あのソラって奴を
ぶっ倒すために➡
敵の本拠地
火ノ寺について知りたい」。
って… これアンタじゃない。
だって なんか生意気だし。
ったく…。
火ノ寺は 木ノ葉随一の忍寺で➡
強固な封印鉄壁は
一度も破られたことがないそうよ。
忍僧たちは 仙族の才と呼ばれる
特別な術を操るとか。
地陸さんは 守護人十二士に
選ばれるくらいだから➡
その強さは 折り紙つきね。
ふ～ん。 そういえばさ
火ノ寺って➡
結構 頭 剃ってないヤツいるよな
なんで？
さぁ？ 例えば 見習いだとか。
あっ そっか！ ヤツは見習いか。
いや 例えばだから。
うん 見習いじゃ しようがねえな。
しばらくは
なまあたたか～く見守ってやる。
まぁ 質問者も
納得したみたいだし➡
これにて終了ってことで。